Yeah, he's like, "Wait a second. Maybe
that was webcam shit." But I need to
look at the freaking code because I need
to have my proxy open. Valentino.
Best part of Viking when you can just,
you know, critical think.
[Music]
So when you're running an enterprise
security program, there are quite a few
things you need to nail before you even
consider doing something like running a
bug bounty program, right? The these are
kind of like the ABCs of enterprise
security. Um obviously you need some
sort of fishing prevention system. You
need an EDR, you need some um
introspection into your environment with
logging. And of course, you need some
sort of patch management system to make
sure that your software is constantly up
to date. And not going to lie, guys,
that last one is a little bit of a pain
in the butt, right? I know you guys know
what I'm talking about with that. It's
it's a lot. And whenever there is
something that's a pain in the butt in
security, what happens? Well, Threat
Locker always comes up with an
innovative solution. And that's exactly
what they've done with Threat Locker
patch management. their team is working
constantly to ensure the software
updates for software in your ecosystem
are audited, categorized, so if there's
like a super severe zero day, you'll
definitely know about it. And then check
for conflicts with other software on
your system before enabling the
enterprise admin to automatically update
or schedule an update in the future. And
I'll just read this little snippet from
their website really quick, which I
loved. It says, "We'll even dare to say
install threat locker patch management
and forget about patch management. We've
got it covered." M that is what you love
to hear. That is what you love to hear,
right? Okay. So, definitely check it
out, guys. threadlocker.com/platform
patch-management or just go to
threadlocker.com and uh and look for the
patchmanagement software. All right,
that's a wrap. Let's go back to the
show.
All right, we're rolling. Valentino, my
man, we've been wanting to do this
episode ever since the live hacking
event in Google. Um, thanks so much for
coming on the pod today.
Yeah, I I am grateful for to be here.
So,
um, yeah, dude. I'm looking at this doc
with the prep for that you've done for
this episode, and it is one of my
favorite types of docs that I like to
see, which is just absolutely stacked
with hacking stories, you know, like
like the I often really like to see, you
know, people bringing on new research
and I really like to see people bringing
on fun bug stories. Those two are the
ones that I get really hyped. So, we've
got tons of really good bug stories in
here. Um, so let's kick it off. Well,
Okay. Typically I I kick it off with a
little bit of a um a little bit of a a
bug story. So let's see what what we've
got here. We've got four different
options. Take your pick, man. Which one
do you want to talk about?
There are so many stories. Uh but I
think I will start with the first. Um so
uh it is pretty simple. I had a Tom cut
instance. So we don't got sometimes
system administrator
uh use a reverse proxy to expose it. So
basically it was exposed with a proxy
but it had the default credentials.
So basically using uh the research uh
published by orange DCA which is called
uh path normalization issues or
something like that. uh you can
basically use dot dot uh semicolon
uh and bypass uh
use a bot traversal to access the
manager
behind the response.
So so what was happening here? So that's
that dot dot semicolon payload, right?
Is that the right one? Yeah. Yeah. So
that's like I freaking love that
research by or what a what a brilliant
way to do it. So I guess what was
happening there was you know you had a
specific path that was allowed by the
reverse proxy and and then you you know
the reverse proxy wasn't seeing dot dot
semicolon as a as a path traversal. Yes.
And then you know the backend server was
and that's what allowed you to get
access to that Tomcat.
Exactly. Just
and I I love it man. There was another
step which when you access with admin
admin the Tomcat manager you basically
weren't allowed to upload files. It was
uh restricted to local host.
So uh that's where I found the JMSX
proxy. Sorry for my pronunciation. Uh
no you're good. You're good. JMX pro
proxy. Okay. So if you can't h upload
the file uh being logged in to tongat
because uh it was restricted to local
host you can basically use that proxy to
sh mx to uh exploit it exploit that and
get basically.
Oh dude this is just check this out.
This is just uh straight up like RC as a
service here. JMX this JMX proxy thing.
Wow. Solid. Okay. So, if if you've ever
if we ever run into those scenarios
where you can't hit, you know, the
traditional Tomcat manager instance like
you would and be able to upload a shell
um because of the uh restrictions to
localhost, then you know we we go
instead and hit this /manager/jmxroxy
and then that one will allow us to
execute code either way.
Yeah. The only problem problem is that
uh you need to have the ro called for to
call that endpoint but sometimes it is
uh misconfigured so you can just call it
you you you need to have the role is
that what you said
yes sometimes people just keep all the
roles without thinking and yeah you can
basically deploy this
classic I love it man that's a good
that's a good takeaway because and I
think I see these often. Man, I I was
very surprised. I can't say the name of
the of the target, but there was a
target I was hacking on once that is
literally like a household name. Like I
used this thing as a kid often like and
on www,
you know, that site.com there was a path
traversal just like this just dot dose
semicolon slash and then it was dropping
you right into some place where you
could execute code. So, I think this
these reverse proxy um you know setups
that a lot of people like to use uh if
you can if you can detect them I think
that there's a a large um surface attack
surface there uh for some sort of
scanner that we haven't really seen hit
hit the scene you know ju just yet of
like okay here are the application
segments you know at slashassets now
we're looking at an S3 bucket you know
at slash app we're looking at this you
know net backend you know at whatever
we're looking at some static enginex
assets or whatever, right? If we can
identify these application segments on a
target, then oftent times there's a lot
of weird vulnerabilities we can do with
path normalization.
Yeah, it is crazy. Orange does all that
stuff and it is crazy. You can get so
many things. Uh yeah.
Yeah. What is this? What is this other
write up you linked here that was on way
back URLs that that uh that isn't up
anymore?
Some Chinese write up or something like
this? I I was stuck in this issue in
that part that I told you I couldn't
upload files
and I found this Chinese blog and and I
and I found that you could be could
exploit that uh that proy. That's that
was the key to
uh that's where the JMX manager thing
came from.
Nice, man. Nice. We'll we'll link that
down in the description. That's that's
hilarious, though. Uh, oh yeah, and they
even list an exploit, Tomcat JamX RC
exploit. Um, very cool.
Yeah, it basically is log poisoning
basically. Uh,
oh, really? Okay, nice. Nice. Log
poisoning, dude. I think log poisoning
is on everybody's radar now ever since
the log forj thing where it's like, oh
my gosh, this has got to be all over the
place. Um,
yes,
that's pretty sick.
Yeah, I definitely recently I've been on
an on something I've been working on.
I've been off of hacking uh almost since
almost since the Google live hacking
event. I've just had a bunch of stuff
come up. I've been working with a couple
companies and just this past couple
weeks I've been back hacking on bug
bounty programs again and uh like blind
XSS in logs or or like you're talking
right here log poisoning with some
server side logic. Um such a fun type of
vulnerability. Uh it it feels a little
wishwashy to me though sometimes because
I'm like you know I'm trying all these
random things. I'm trying to guess
what's happening on the back end. Uh,
and I just hope something calls back,
you know.
Yes. I love to to blackbox the the
hugging is
it's a totally different skill, right? I
mean, than than white box uh testing.
You know, there there are a lot of
really talented white box testers that I
know, but when you see a really talented
blackbox tester, it's like they've got
some like six sense of what's happening
with the application. And and I think
all of us have that to some degree,
right, that have been successful in the
industry. But there are some people that
are just like, "Yeah, that is definitely
how they coded it. Let me just say I'm
like, what the heck?"
Yeah. In the old event, it it seemed
like that. Like,
yeah,
I I was just,
oh yeah, this might work. And it worked,
but it does in in it didn't make sense.
Then it took like an entire week to find
the the cause. It's like
Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely, man. All right.
Well, you you presented your bug. You
you proved your your hackerhood to the
listeners. Um, I'll give you a quick
intro and then we'll hit some of these
other bugs real quick. Um, so as I
mentioned guys, this is Valentino. Uh, I
met Valentino at the Google Live Hacking
event in Tokyo. Or maybe it was the one
before that.
I think Yeah, in Vegas. That's right. It
was in Vegas that we met the first time.
But then in in Tokyo, we were kind of
neck andneck for the for the MVH there.
and uh sitting next to Valentino at
dinner, you know, we we talked about a
lot of bugs and and I was really
impressed with his methodology. So, I've
been wanting I wanted to get him on the
the the live talk at uh at the Google
event, but we didn't get to do it
because of uh timelines being
constricted, but um we do have the
opportunity to do that now. So, I'm uh
I'm very excited. Um let's go ahead and
and jump through the rest of these,
Valentino. Um and talk talk through some
of these. Well, no, no. All right, let
me back out. you've already proved your
worth. Now, let's go into a little bit
of history. How did you how did you get
into infosc and hacking? And then we'll
get into the rest of the bugs that
you've popped.
Okay. So, I got into infosc when I was
around 12 years old. I didn't even know
what I was doing.
Today, I kind of know a bit. Uh so in
that time uh I was playing a lot of
Minecraft like
12 hours I get a day and my parents were
telling me please you need to study stop
playing that game. Uh so one day I got
bored of the game and I started to uh
learn how to make servers. So by by
building servers I noticed that uh let's
say uh the servers are basically
basically networks. You have multiple
mini games and you have like a an
authentication server where you log in
then a lobby and then mult you can
access uh whatever miniame you want. So
I noticed that the mapping proxy was
just specifying each miniame as a as a
port. So I I I thought what if I just
access the mini game directly? It's like
uh no-brainer. And so I I did and it
worked and it was my first uh issue.
Dude, what what how hype must have you
been at like 12 or 13 to been like,
"Yes, it worked." You know,
I was scanning entire BPS providers
like the entire blocks all night.
Oh, the ASN ranges. Yeah.
My parents told me, "What is this charge
about the BPS?" And I told them, "No,
no, no worries. I am learning server
administration."
There you go. Nice, man. I I also
started hacking when I was like 12. And
uh the sketchy stuff that we do at that
at that age to learn how to hack stuff,
man. It's it's great. But it was such an
exciting time, too, you know, like when
you first pop something and something
actually worked, some exploit actually
worked. It's like h that's the best
feeling.
Yeah.
I I think uh I think Minecraft as well,
dude. I think Minecraft has been a
what a what a um a piece of software
that just pushes people towards highly
technical roles, right? Like not only
does the game, you know, have a lot of
programming like components with all the
stuff you can do um with like the
buttons and automation and stuff like
that, but also you know this whole
concept of hosting servers and you know
running that business or running that
from a hacking perspective has just
brought so many people into the
technical realm.
Yeah, it is crazy. I know many people
that are gamers that were gamers and
then hackers. It's like really common.
Yeah.
Yeah. Very common flow. Um, very nice,
man. So, so you you got into it a little
bit at 12. Where does the story pick up
after that?
After that, I uh my well uh there were
some protections that were implemented
and I liked the idea of uh bypassing
those protections.
So I editor was a protection that
basically checked that the original IP
was local host and well it was by
possible.
Oh my gosh.
You can just by spoof IP and that's it.
Yeah.
Oh my gosh, dude. And then that's
another set of uh vulnerabilities on all
these Minecraft targets. Wow. It is
similar to to course I think uh the
origin thing and
yeah it is I I I learned so many things
in in Minecraft that I applied in web
hacking is like so nice.
Yeah dude absolutely. So how did you
make the jump from hacking Minecraft
stuff over to being a pentester or bug
bounty hunter? So at that time my
parents uh basically restricted my
access to the computer.
Yeah.
So classic I I had to study in school
for uh two years. Uh and then uh when I
was uh 16 uh when I was uh uh when I got
better at the school, I returned to
hacking but uh knowing knowing the stuff
behind like I started learning
programming
and then I I learned Java the basics of
security and then I started uh with hack
hackots. uh it is a lab
uh for CTF
and yeah that's the the point where I
learn a lot of stuff and I started
hacking
uh with labs not with real world targets
like
yeah yeah I think I think you know
likewise I when I was 12 13 14 15 a lot
of the stuff I was hacking on was you
know illegal illegal hacking stuff uh
you know things that I didn't have
authorization to hack on um because I
think at the time there wasn't labs as
easily accessible as well or at least I
didn't know about them right um and so
then you know once we get access to I I
also remember when I went to college you
know when I was 18 or so I I like
figured out oh there's this thing called
metas-loitable or whatever right where
you can or damn vulnerable web
application where you can set that stuff
up and then you can start like honing
your skills and it's based off of real
vulnerabilities and uh you can do it in
a lot more ethical way. But I'm sure
that there are a lot of kids out there
even today that are just like, "Yeah, I
hadn't really put the thought into, oh,
maybe there's a lab out there where I
can practice this rather than just
popping shells on people's web servers
randomly."
Yeah, that's that's bad. Yeah. I The
problem is that kids might think it is
fun, but Yeah, it is fun, but it is
illegal, so don't do it.
Exactly. Right. Exactly. I'm looking at
the rest of the notes here, man. And it
looks like you you did the OCP and then
quote, "After getting that
certification, I received some job
offers and the day after my 18th
birthday, I started my first pentesting
job." Dude, that is a pretty sick
record, man. Uh like starting your your
first pentesting job the day after you
turn 18. Um what what So you were
getting the SCP before you were 18 even?
Uh I started the recipe when I was uh 17
because I
I I had to do the final year in my
school but I choose to not do it. I
choose to do it at h to do from h from
home homeschooling.
Uh so
homeschooling. Yeah.
I I just spend like two days a week for
school and the entire week for hacking.
So,
dude, okay, my man, you were also
homeschooled. I I was homeschooled all
of my my childhood. Like, and it was
great because I whenever I was hacking
something, right, or doing some
programming job like I was when I was
younger, I would often go up to my mom
and be like, "Hey, mom. So, uh, I got
this like programming job. I'm going to
do this for the next couple days, and
then I'll catch up on math or English,
right, or whatever, right?" And she was
like, "All right, just don't, you know,
way to go, honey. Like, I'm glad you're
making money. Just make sure you don't
get behind on school." And then as long
as I got my school caught back up, then
we were good to go. And I just I credit
that with so much of my success, you
know, as a as a hacker and as a
programmer, just being able to have that
flexibility and entrepreneurial spirit
at a young age and then being able to
implement it without, you know, having
to be locked up at school all day.
Yeah. In those times, you have so much
free time that you can just uh be quick
with the school and and and and hack.
Exactly, man. Exact. I love that. That's
That's amazing. That you're one of the
only other people I've ever met that,
you know, was homeschooled as well and
used that time to go to go hack stuff.
That's that's clutch, man. Is that Is
that common at all in in Argentina or is
that um
um No, it is not common. Uh but
there are some people that can do it. Uh
but yeah, I I just did the last year,
but because I was tired of school, it's
like five hours a day, five days a week.
It was
a lot. Like
it was it is a lot. Yeah. And and and
shout out to your parents for for
allowing you to do that. I mean, I think
that's that's pretty cool that they were
open to that sort of thing. I know I
know here in the US homeschooling is
like skyrocketing like like like the the
amount I think it's grown 50%
year-over-year for the past like five
years. Like it's just getting massive.
Um
and and so I I really I was really glad
to see that. And sometimes it can be
done really really poorly and the people
are not learning their stuff and they're
getting socially isolated. But for me,
you know, with with uh with parents that
were actively involved and I still got
to play my sports and, you know, had
community outside um as well as a a you
know, very intentional education at
home, uh it worked super well.
Yeah, it depends on the parents and
yeah, it can be very well. So, yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Um All right. So, we're 18
years old. We have a pentesting job.
We're 18 years old in one day and we're
we're starting a pen testing job. Um,
how do you get into Bug Bounty and how
did you get invited to the Bug SWAT
event uh for for Google?
Uh, it was really random. Like I I think
most things that happened with uh Google
were random for me at least. I was
thinking, okay, I saw a tweet that I
asked, do you want to hi in a private
event and I say said, okay, I I sent the
form and and and I thought, yeah, they
are not going to call me. H
there are more qualified people than
than me. So yeah, I I I waited and I got
the email and I said, "What?" So I I
started learning
uh how to hack AI
and in the first event it was really
hard. Uh and another thing is that
they just told me do you want to go to
Vegas? And I and I said
uh I can't go I I can't go to Vegas
because I I can't pay for the the flight
and the hotel. It is expensive. Yeah.
So they told me, "What if you if we pay
for it?"
And I said, "Definitely." Yes, of
course. Yeah.
And and I and I went and
dude, that's crazy, man. Like so at that
point had you submitted a lot of bugs to
Google or
uh I think um I I sent like two bugs
that weren't that great and and
I I registered to to the Google um to
the Google account in in the same month
I did the the hacking event
and but I didn't particularly sent uh
high impact box and I got the
invitation. Um in that moment I thought
why I got invitation
but uh yeah I I knew I had to to put my
efforts.
Yeah. Yeah. This is what I'm saying man.
Everybody's still early on Google,
right? Like this when was this
Valentino? This was last Vegas, right?
This is Vegas 2024. Uh this was uh in
2023.
2023. Okay. Gotcha. 2023 Vegas was when
uh you first went with the Google with
the Google program.
Yes.
Nice. Okay. Yeah. So guys, it's still
early with Google, man. I mean, just a
couple years ago, not even not even two
years ago, one year ago and some change.
Valentino is like submitting a form,
submitting two, you know, crappy bugs
and then getting an invite to Vegas. So
um it's it's an amazing opportunity.
Definitely spend some time on Google. It
but Dantino man it is kind of scary
right I mean hacking on Google they they
have a lot of obfusation there's a lot
of protojson right um there's a lot of
uh you know very minified products and
and so what are your what are your what
are your tips and tricks on on hacking
on on Google for the listener that that
wants to take up that opportunity. For
me it is uh getting really used with one
product product. Uh if you can talk with
the security team because they know a
lot of stuff and basically the thing
that worked for me is
stopping stop looking at the code. Stop
look looking at the requests.
close the proy like
Valentino my guy this is crazy advice
but it it it worked for you right I've
seen it I've seen it work for you
because there are so many things that
happen in in this application that you
need some time to think what is
happening in the back end what what is
what is the application loading how you
can uh what how you need to think like
the developer
It's like poker. I think you need to get
in the in the head of the uh people that
made application
and then you need to look I I look for
patterns. I I try things that are weird
and and breaking stuff and then I see uh
what happened and how it happened. All
the all the bugs I found during the
event I didn't use. I I
Dude, that is just absolutely nuts. And
it's crazy to me because, you know, when
we were sitting at that dinner, right,
that awesome dinner in in Tokyo and we
were chatting about the bugs that you
found, I was listening to this and I was
like, "Ah, yeah, duh. Why didn't I like
all of the attack pictures that you came
up were were so like simple but creative
and like showed a depthful understanding
of the product, right? And where the
security boundaries are." And I'm really
like I'm glad to have you on the pod,
dude, because I think there are a lot of
different types of hackers out there,
right? There are people that are just
obscenely technical and will just like,
you know, and and looking at some of the
stuff in here, you got a little bit of
both for sure, right? Uh but, you know,
there are some people that are just they
all they do is focus on like the the
white box parts, the code where they can
the part where they can get their hands
on the code. They read it, they fully
understand it, they bend it, right? And
and then there's there's people that are
that are just um unbelievably creative
with their attack vectors, right? And
and I there's such a beauty to that
latter piece, right? And the the the the
first is I think more of a science. The
latter is more of an art, right? Where
it's like, you know, crafting these
these really um creative uh attack
scenarios. Um, and and to be honest for
the listener, uh, I think you should be
encouraged because for for the creative
piece, there are a couple hackers that I
know that are are not very very
technical. I'm thinking of one friend
that I have that has earned, you know,
multiple five figure bounties just from
being a insanely creative hacker uh, and
just using the UI, right? No, no proxy,
no dev tools, no nothing. Just clickity
clickity clickity click. So, it
definitely is possible, right?
Yeah. And it is crazy. Uh I I I couldn't
find issues using the broady and all the
things and then I closed the broady and
it I started finding a lot of uh bugs
that were crazy. It's I I I started
thinking I think it is a critical thing.
But there you go. I I would add another
thing which is abstract thinking is
really important.
The problem is there are hackers that um
well it is not a problem. It is h
something. But the thing is that there
are hackers that need to know all the
details like uh the code everything. But
uh sometimes you need to really um
understand that you will lack
information and you need to be
comfortable with lacking information and
guessing a bit.
Dang, dude. That's deep. That that hits
me right in the heart, man. I'm one of
those guys that needs to see all of the
pieces, right? I'm not I'm not very good
at not having, you know, some of those
pieces. And and for me, you know, when
I'm hacking on stuff, I really I do try
to line all those pieces up in my brain.
Like like uh you know, I'll I'll write
it down. I'll map it out. I'll draw it.
I've got these big yellow notepads that
I have around that I just sketch and
like draw and and try to get it, you
know, all in one piece. But I need to be
more comfortable with the abstract,
right? With with the with the uncertain
pieces. Um, and and just kind of take
guesses at what's happening or or
educated, you know, guesses at at what
could be happening. That's that's pretty
rad.
It is hard. It is hard for me. It is
hard to to do the thing you like having
knowing the entire application deeply.
It is hard for me because I I get
distracted a lot. But but I kind of feel
it is easier to just have some some
information and just
make an inference like
inference with abstract thinking and it
sometimes works.
Yeah.
Absolutely man. All right. Let's let's
take a look at a couple examples of
that. Um, you know, one of the ones that
was interesting that kind of that kind
of um highlights I think that that
abstract thinking was your uh
vulnerability that was disclosed at
Marcato Libre
uh with with the HTML sanitizer.
Can you talk a little bit about that
bug? That's a disclosed report, so we'll
put it in the description for anybody
who wants to follow along. But um can
you talk a little bit about what you
found there?
Yeah, that was my first crazy bug. like
it was my first the first time I I I I
thought in abstract terms.
Uh I basically
um uh saw a request that basically in
Merc you can sell and buy products. So I
I tried making a buying a product and
then making a a claim
and then I saw the request uh with a
claim and HTML code and I I and I said
what is happening here? It's like why it
is sending HTML code. So,
so this when you say a claim, is this
like when you've bought something and
you need to like get some support or
something like that from the seller or
Yes, exactly. Uh, basically you're uh
trying to make a a claim to to uh return
to the product uh or to say something is
wrong basically.
Ah, okay. Okay. So, you've got a support
complaint and and you're and you're
trying to get support for the product,
maybe even return it. And when you do
that, the message that you send contains
HTML in it.
Exactly. Yes,
dude. Don't you love to see that though?
Don't like I my heart like skips a
little beat like whenever I see uh
those, you know, encoded HTML tags
inside of inside of my request. I'm
like, yes, I know that there's going to
be something interesting here.
Yeah, it is like awesome. But it was
there was a sanitizer but
and that sanitiz sanitizer was h custom
I think. So I I was able to
make uh some uh guesses and bypass it.
It's like and that bypass was crazy
because um
basically
uh it had like a low list of tags and
when I not when I sent uh multiple pags
uh it was maybe it is hard to see like
uh the picture but uh there were many
open tags that you can if you send
multiple open tags
And then a malaious payload, it
basically bypasses the the filter for
some reason.
Dude, it's crazy, man. I It's crazy how
some of this stuff happens, right? Like,
so you just have open P tab, open P tab,
open P tag, open P tag, open P tag, and
then like your XSS payload, and the
thing just starts reading the P tags.
It's like, all right, yep, it's another
P. All right, whatever. It's fine. You
know, just let it through. And then it
just opens it. That's nuts, man. Nesting
stuff. Nesting stuff is is really
important when uh attacking a sanitizer.
Yeah, it is. It's it is uh I saw it is
really important uh with uh the logs
made by MISO.
Exactly. Yeah. Yeah. They they there's
so there have been so many um DOM DOM
purify bypasses because of the depth
restraints and uh essentially having
namespace confusions because of the the
sort of stack reaching maximum depth and
then um you know tags being normalized
to the same you know spot within the the
nesting. So it's pretty amazing. Yeah,
it is like and and the the more the most
like crazy thing is that in that time I
didn't even look at the code. So I I I I
don't know the root cause.
I don't know that you know that would
drive me crazy. That would drive me like
I cannot believe that you didn't go back
and read the freaking sanitizer code
afterwards, man. Like I mean unless it's
happening on the server side and you
can't but you're just like P tech p oh
it worked. Let's go submit the report.
I'm like dude.
Yeah it was crazy. And and then they
they put don't purify. So it
Oh jeez. Yeah. Okay.
I think
bummer man. Bummer. Well, I I I see
you've got um a section of this doc
where you you say that there are, you
know, some patterns that are sort of
follow this uh this this structure um in
in other pieces of hacking. Can you talk
a little bit about that?
Uh yes, sure. Uh there were
um h do you mean the part uh the
patterns and the perfection?
Yeah, exa exactly. Yeah.
Oh yeah. Uh so in this uh vulnerability
I I reflected on it and I think um there
are uh some things that uh we can take
uh here uh there there was a an allow
list uh so you you could basically wrap
a malicious object inside the uh an
analog lo and that bypasses the the
mitigations. It is
really interesting because it is similar
to insecur visualizations
where you have an allow allow allow list
and then you can just wrap evil objects
inside and it works.
Yeah. Yeah. I I think it's really
important that we reflect upon those
sort of uh principles within hacking
that makes us much better hackers is
when we see this higher level pattern,
right? And what what you're pointing out
here is that sometimes there are allow
lists, right? And the inside of those
allow lists, you know, there can be
subobjects, right? That that should not
be allowed. Uh and and the the thing
that's assessing it may only go, you
know, one layer deep, right? So there's
this nesting part, there's this allow
list part. We see this in in SAML
bypasses. We see this in uh you know des
serialization. We see this in in
sanitizing bugs, right? HTML sanitizing
bugs. Um definitely a common pattern
that hackers need to be familiar with
and apply to different areas of of
hacking. Yeah, it is is it is really
cool how you can apply one thing can
take one technique for from I don't know
blockchain or like crypto crypto hacking
and apply it somewhere else. I one day I
did an experiment. I read a a blog
talking about uh crypto bag. I didn't
understand almost anything but I I read
Cash
many times and and I and I thought this
issue is is universal like race
conditions some multcapes it's like in
bugs they are like patterns in in in so
like
all over the place all over the place
man yeah especially crypto because it's
such an a unique area you know with
re-entrance mergency attacks and stuff
like that. You know, trying to take
those principles and apply them to other
areas and and to take, you know, the
areas of traditional web security and
apply them uh to other things, right? We
see this stuff happening with uh with AI
AI related vulnerabilities and and every
new area that pops up. There's the same
old problems that we have from before
just taking a different form. Um all
right, man. Now, now we've we've kind of
gone through a couple of these. Let's
let's hit the the onslaught of really
crazy bugs that you have um in here and
hear a bunch of stories. So um I'm
looking right now at the command
injection in Vertex AI, one of the
Google products. And this one I read
your little write up on here beforehand.
So cool, dude. So tell the listeners
about that. I think they're really going
to enjoy it. And and um can I share this
doc this related draft document or
um
Yes.
Yeah. Okay, cool. I'll uh I'll share it
and maybe it'll help the users visualize
a little bit. Uh the common inception in
Verti. Uh
it was another crazy bug.
I found without looking at the
Valentino, stop, man. What are you?
Please don't do this to me. Oh my gosh.
Okay. What? Tell me about it. Tell me
about It is really fun because uh it was
basically inverted AI you have like a a
feature where you can uh uh text uh
prompts with different models. So I
noticed uh you can embed uh
content and then you can uh use a
feature called get code which generates
code uh to call the the APIs with your
test prompt. So I thought
what if I just can use a a code quote
and and escape the the and perform
command insertion. It didn't work. But
then I thought, well, images are
interesting
have been interesting uh with Google. So
I just
put an image and and and escape in in
the image URL and then I got the command
injection there.
Okay. Okay. Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. Valentina, hold up. You can't just
say and then I got the command
injection. So Okay. So, what's going on
here is this file that's that's being
uploaded, if I'm understanding this
write up correctly. Yes.
This file that's being uploaded is is a
JSON file, right? That represents what?
A prompt.
Oh, sorry. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yes. I I I skipped that part.
You're good. You're good. Tell me about
it.
So, basically,
the problem is that the the communion
needed the user to copy and paste the
content in the chat. So it was too much
interaction.
So I decided to find an indirect way of
uh introducing that uh malicious
content. So I I found another feature
called uh prompt management.
That's where you can import a prompt
with with a JSON file with some uh
variables and data. And yeah the the
attack is basically the user downloads a
print file imports it and then after
using the get code it inserts the
command escaping the URL URL which is
inserted in that code that
okay okay okay hold up hold up a second
so uh so you're you're taking a JSON
attacker prepares a you know yes
prompt template or whatever JSON file
and then they upload that to Vertex AI,
right? Yes.
And now the the prompt that you've
prepared is in their Vert.ex AI and then
you said they hit the get code button.
What does the get code button do?
The the the get code basically uh
generates uh code to call the the Google
AI APIs uh to test the brunt.
Ah okay. Okay. So then this allows this
gives you some way to um use this
specific prompt that you've prepared via
the Google APIs.
Yes. Yes.
Ah okay. And then when you do that it it
generates some some code either some is
it is it bash python what did you say it
was in this scenario? uh you have uh
many options like uh cool bash
well bash is cool then python and nodejs
etc. So,
wow. And then and and so what was
happening there was, you know, it would
generate it and it would somehow pass in
this prompt, you know, to to the the I
guess curl, let's just say curl in this
scenario in this curl request, right? So
maybe it's using like, you know, binary
data or just like dash d or whatever in
curl, right? Yes. And then and then
inside of that JSON you were able to
provide something that would break out
of the JSON object within the the so
it's like a command line argument
injection.
Uh it was like a just
command injection without anything
tricks like just h the end end of line.
Okay. and you need to close the
multi-line H uh thing and then you can
just insert it.
It wasn't like complicated at all.
Nice. Nice. So um I've seen this kind of
bug several times and it's it was really
cool because the first time I saw it, it
was done by um Ini. I don't know if you
know the hacker Ini. He's kind of OG in
the in the bug bounty space. He did the
ticket trick um research back in the day
and we were at a live hacking event and
he he got showand tell. He was like one
of the best bugs of the event because he
said um rce via content injection and
because he was able to generate like
like you did here, you know, inject into
a code block that was supposed to be
copied and pasted into, you know,
somebody's code, you know, into their
PHP file at the time, right? And he was
able to just specify arbitrary um
arbitrary PHP within that and and then
it would run on the victim server. And I
think that this is a uh pretty niche
niched bug, right? It's not it's it's uh
something that you see pretty often, but
not a lot of people try is content
injection inside of these um very
multicontextual environments, right?
Where there's lots of context. There's
the curl context, there's the JSON
context, there's the HTTP context. It's
very very cool attack vector. Yeah,
basically I mean it requires some
interaction but still the origin is
trusted so you need to be careful.
Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely. Um all right
let's let's see. All right. Vertex AI.
That one was pretty cool. Google gave
you a good a good bounty for that. Let's
come back to some of these other stories
that you have up at the top. Um you
mentioned deserialization earlier. It
looks like you've done some work with
.NET and Java deserialization. Do you
want to talk about one of those two?
Um, I I I won't say I I know much about
uh visualizations
because I found I I I found the bath and
I read the the entire the entire paper
and that that was it. like I I I I did
some research like two weeks uh just to
exploit the bug and and then I I I
forgot about it like
Yeah. What what paper were you reading
at the time for dialization that you
used to exploit this? I read
many papers written by Alvaro Munos
which are so great to to start with uh
the realization and then I read uh this
massive paper by Pasilo which is
awesome like it it I I I feared this
realizations way way back but that paper
made me realize is it is very fun and
and interesting to play.
Yeah, dude. This guy Pod. Oh my gosh.
This is Chuty PD.
Yeah,
dude. He's he's unbelievable, man. I've
I've uh I've read some We've covered
some of his stuff on the pod before. I'd
love to have him on the pod. Um the
stuff that he comes out with uh
specifically surrounding the pone
research that he does is like
unbelievable. Um, very crazy stuff. Um,
all right. All right. What's this? All
right. Jumping down the list. What is
this argument injection to LFR in
parsing component? Oh, there
there was a time uh I had um it was this
was a white h kind of hacking. So when I
looked at the code, it seemed uh safe,
but I found a way to set an argument
and then uh it it called a a specific
parsing tool. So I needed to basically
uh read the manual and and and see which
arguments I can use to get uh some
impact. So I I I reverse engineered the
binary
a bit and then I I found a way to
trigger a server side uh request for
sharing with a local file read and leak
files.
Oh my gosh. So so it was a it was a um
argument injection some is this is in a
web app I presume?
Uh yes. Yes.
Okay. So it's an argument injection from
a web app. web app is calling some sort
of command line utility. That command
line utility you go in reverse find, you
know, you've got an argument injection
in there. So you add an argument that
takes a file from the user's local
machine and somehow yeetss it out to
some, you know, throws it to some
attacker controlled server. Is that
right?
Yeah. Like to be more specific,
basically uh it prepares a request and
it read a file that is is supposed to be
a header with some credentials or some
data. So it sends that header in the
request that that is supposed to go to a
server legitimate server.
But you can just put uh the etc password
in the header value and and it works.
You check your server's logs and it's
like, you know, authorization bearer
root, you know, it just jumps the whole
Etsy password file.
Yeah,
dude. I love that, man. Uh hacky stuff
like that where it's like you get these
malformed HTTP requests and somehow your
server catches it. It's like, oh my
gosh, I love this.
It is.
That's that's beautiful, man. That's
really beautiful. Um All right, dude. Uh
I've I'm I'm going down here. I'm
looking at some of the other stuff
you've got. I really liked this um this
thing that you um called uh free after
use, right? Not use after free, but free
after use. I thought that was really
funny. Can you tell us about that
specific vulnerability? What happened
there and how um the listeners can look
for a similar vulnerability?
Yeah, basically there
I was looking for author authorization
issues like IOR and all that.
But uh it was tricky to find idors
because they are so common that are fits
uh very quickly. So I thought
uh why what if I just access uh
basically the concept free after use is
looking for
moments where the application does uh
some weird stuff when a us a specific
user accesses an a specific resource. In
this case, an own an owner of a resource
accessed his uh metrics
for instance and then uh I could
basically
um when it when the owner accesses the
metrics,
everyone can access the metrics. It's
like
when they that that's why I called it a
how is called free after use
the user
not use after free
the owner uses turns the the the the
component and it is free like
then it becomes free for everyone that's
hilarious man so I I think I think this
is a pretty niche scenario I I have seen
it before for sure where you know some
routes will just be for some reason um
like presented like that it's an
authorization issue Um but one of the
other places where you often see this is
caching related vulnerabilities right
like if there is a server at some point
somewhere that is caching whatever
resource and then serving it you know
and another person hits that resource um
once it's already in the cache then it's
not hitting any of the backend logic
it's just presenting that same data
again to the other user um so very
similar to web cache deception in that
way
yeah it is really similar to that yeah
and I know that I think it Yeah.
Yeah. He's like, "Wait a second. Maybe
that was webc's half shit." But I need
to look at the freaking code cuz I need
to have my proxy open. Valentino.
Oh my god, dude.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that that's definitely a good one.
Yeah. when I for instance relating to
the sanitizer bypass earlier when I read
the don't verify misconfigurations I
bypasses blog by Misu I thought oh this
is pretty similar to what I did uh yeah
this is this is the bug this
so so I'm wondering Valentino I I know
you know how old are you right now do
you mind sharing on the pod or
Uh what the uh thing? Sorry, I I
How old are you?
Oh. Uh now 21.
21. Okay. So, you're a younger guy,
right? You're a younger guy in this
scene. You've been doing this for for
for three years. Um I think you've had a
lot of success here, clearly finding a
lot of vulnerabilities. Um, do you think
that your evolution, you know, your
growth as a hacker will come with
understanding some of these things at a
more technically depthful level or are
you going to try to spend time trying to
foster and grow in yourself that
creative and abstract thinking? Which
way do you see yourself going as a
hacker? And maybe it's both, but I'm
just curious.
Uh, I think there is a limit to
creativity. M so I think and there there
is lack in that creativity so I I think
I'm going to go h to the more technical
route um
to really understand uh the deeper parts
so yeah I think that's a good idea
I I think that's a good progression and
I think you're you're right that there
is luck and there is limits to
creativity um kind of crazy though that
you place second at the Google live
hacking event off of that. So, uh I
think maybe you're like your creativity
levels are like super high from a um you
know from a baseline perspective. Um and
and let me ask you this. You know, you
you sort of um mentioned uh several
times throughout this this pod that you
think that a lot of this has to do with
spending a lot of time on an
application, right? On the pod we call
it getting intimate with the
application. You know, you know, you
know everything about this application.
You can, you know, hold it in your
hands. You're like, I know exactly what
you are. Um so yeah I think you know
that do do you find that that creativity
gets spurred more after you feel like
you've understood all the parts of the
application um or do you think it's more
uh in as a part of that process of
understanding everything about the
application?
I think uh basically playing around with
an application for a lot
of time like I I have been sending bugs
like to a single application for at
least two years or it's like
All right guys listen to what Valentino
says here. Say say it again for the
people in the back. Valentino say it
again. I have been finding bugs in a
single application for two years but two
years
two years guys listen to what Valentino
is saying you so many people Valentino
so many val people Valentino will say to
me ah I've been hacking on this app for
so long I can't figure it out can't get
any bugs I'm like how long have you been
hacking they're like two days and I'm
like dude like like you haven't spent
any time on this I'm still reading the
docs two days in, you know, sometimes.
So, I think it's really key what you
mentioned here.
Yeah. And sometimes you don't need to
spend like eight hours a day in a single
application every every day. like
in in the first year I I spend like I
just look at the at application like uh
four hours then the next month uh
uh 12 hours and like keep revisiting the
the application keep going back and
check new things new new thoughts uh I
found in those two years I found most of
of the bugs in three months like I
started popping the box when I really
understood the application like
like a user like a someone that just
tries the application like uses the
application.
Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely man that that is
super pivotal and I wonder Valentino do
you you know you mentioned you said you
earlier that sometimes you get bored
quickly um do like but you're you're
spending a lot of times on these
applications. Do you think that you're
like do you have to force yourself to
refocus on some of these apps? Do you
get bored with them and then but force
yourself to come back to them?
Uh sometimes I get extremely interested
in in in an application that I sometimes
I have a a different problem which is I
want to focus on Google cloud and I
can't because I I I I keep going back to
the same application. It's like a
visation.
Uh M
like I I know there are there are more
bugs
but sometimes I for instance with Google
cloud which is a a target I I really
I am really starting to like
I really want to hack there but I get
like distracted all the time like
it's like
I
is it do you get distracted by new
applications or by older applications or
by both? I get distracted by everything
like
I start reading the the docs of Versai
and I I start thinking how what are are
the differences between you know the
there are different servers in different
regressions and what what are the
differencees between the languages or
the encodings in different servers and I
like I like crazy things that
probably won't work. Like do you know
the orange DCA for instance published a
blog where he
the what
orange DCA?
I don't I don't think I know it. No, he
published a blog about encodings with
SQL.
Ah, the is it the is this the Defcon
talk on like injecting
uh like at the binary protocol for SQL?
Oh, no. It it
was a CTF challenge.
I don't think I've seen it. Like I I one
day I I decided to read all the CTF
challenges by the biologist because he's
a really cool researcher and one write
up was that an A with a a specific
encoding is converted to a an anki a and
you can basically bypass the admin check
or things like that. And I thought that
might work in Google cloud but if if I I
start thinking about many things and I
can't focus on a single thing right now.
It's like
yeah that's a problem.
Yeah that's that is one of the problems
with some of these big targets right
like Google cloud or AWS and stuff.
There's so many ideas kind of bouncing
around and and sometimes they're a
little technically difficult to
implement. And so I find myself sitting
and scheming and writing down and stuff
like that. And then I realize, yeah,
dude, but the only way I'm actually
going to find vulnerabilities is if I
try stuff. If I actually like go and
technically implement it, right? So I
got to pause for a second and then make
sure I'm I'm keeping my thorough put of
of like things that I've tried. I I got
to keep that high so that I can keep my
vulner output high. And Google is so
massive and so like like it
at at first it I was scared of hacking
Google.
Same.
That's if you feel like comfortable
hacking Google then you start finding
stuff.
It's like Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. It's it is a scary target
but it's definitely doable man.
Definitely doable.
Um let let's jump to this section. Uh I
I love this section you've entitled
issues in file extension validation
components. Um because you've got two
pretty solid checks that I always check
for as well here. Uh and they they
really do help often. So talk about
these two um two tips you have for the
listeners on bypassing uh file extension
validation checks.
So basically uh whenever you have a file
extension validator
you can try stuff like the null bite uh
etc. But in in my case, I I I found a
component that
basically in the back end somewhere
hidden was h
crafting an URL and you can basically
you you could basically
um
do that HTML
uh how is that called like
hashtag
the hashtag and that PNG
Basically the PNG was allowed and the
HTML was disallowed. So basically the
URI parser ignores the rest of the
hashtag. So you can basically bypass the
filter that way. And
yeah, dude, I love both this one and the
question mark, right? because it it it
takes it it takes advantage of the
differences between which characters are
special characters in a file context
versus in a actual HTTP context, right?
You know, a hashtag is a perfectly valid
character in in a file name, but in the
HTTP context that is the beginning of
the the hash fragment, right? Which
truncates the rest of the of the
request. Um, so very solid. I love to
see that. That's that's great.
Yeah, it it is amazing. like the last
research made by orange DCA with the
question mark as well like yeah it's
amazing absolutely um you got another
one here what is this one uppercase
the next one is like simpler because it
was just
XML
with an uppercase that was it like
basically some validators h have a y
list or blacklist uh with that only
checks uh lowerase characters and it
doesn't check like uh it isn't case
insensitive basically
dude I will never forget to check this
because of one freaking live hacking
event and you guys have heard me talk
about it on the pod before listeners so
it's this live hacking met with freaking
Matias Carlton uh he had a crit that all
on a on a piece of um scope that all of
us had seen and he bypassed like a
reverse proxy because of one capital
letter. We were all like, "Man, if we
could only get access to his admin
panel, we could only get access to this
admin panel." And he just take one of
the letters and the last letter and he
converted it to uppercase and it let him
in and I was like, "Ah, I will never
forget to do this ever again." Um, so
that's that I think that's one of the
beauties of the live hacking event,
right, Valentino? where it's like, you
know, you see all the things that other
people have tried and you know how hard
you are banging your head up against the
same scope trying trying and the way you
see other people solve it and it's so
like infuriating that you didn't solve
that that you never ever forget in your
life, you know, to do that attack vector
ever again.
Yeah. sometimes that that I I I I look
at at the at the show and tell I think
oh my god I I this is like something I I
will never think like so creative and so
like but simple at the same time like
yeah there's there's both extremes
they're like wow yeah I was never even
close to that but the ones that stick
with me the most are the ones that are
like oh that was right in front of me
I'm such an idiot how did I not try that
yeah that is painful Yeah,
it's painful, man.
All right, I'm going to jump down to
this last one and then we're going to
call it a wrap for the day. Um, this was
a write up on your blog. Um, and just
kind of have a couple SQL uh injection
vulnerabilities, right? Um, this is
PMBB. Uh, and one of the ones that I
kind of wanted to point out here is that
you had an authenticated curf to SQLI
within this um or write up, right? which
I think is just a really good uh thing
for for the the listeners to understand
because a lot of people would think okay
SQLI like why would I need to seurf that
well you know from an from an
unauthenticated perspective sometimes
you can't even access these endpoints
but if you if you are able to do a
cross-sight request forgery and trigger
the an SQL injection in the back end
your curf can result in something
massive like a serverside vulnerability
right like SQLI or oftent times you see
rce as
Um, so yeah, dude, it was great to see
that right up here. And did you how did
you learn about that technique? Was that
you just kind of um coming, you know,
out of your head there or did you see
somebody who who had implemented this
before?
Um,
I basically had the SQL inception and I
thought
yeah, this is like really not great
uh because you needed like credentials.
So I thought well it is just a get
request so I can use a crossite request
for J and I did like it was like
like intuitive like uh just Yeah. Yeah.
And and I've actually had a a good
amount of success with these actually
working in a in a bug bounty
environment. Um because a lot of times
people will be like ah you know admin
surfs it's kind of hard to prove but
specifically within a um uh and not not
in this scenario you know this is a
different scenario but specifically
within a WordPress environment where you
can create you know you can install the
same plugin and if there's like a curve
to rce or curve to SQL in that plugin
then um you know you can prove to the
triagers hey this works on an admin for
sure and uh and has a large impact like
an SQL in rce
Um, so I I think that's a really good uh
takeaway in these environments.
Yeah, it is. It is really good. Yeah.
Nice, man. Um, I I I did forget about
this this AI hacking section down here
at the bottom. Did you have any
comments? Uh, I I've got to wrap up here
in about uh 10 minutes, but did you have
any any um tips you wanted to give the
listeners on the AI hacking experiences
you've had with Google or or outside of
Google over the past uh year or two?
Yeah, basically what I I would say is uh
please always take into into always
think models are super inconsistent.
So try many variations, try opening new
chats, try uh if you if you trigger the
bug,
don't don't get uh scared if it doesn't
work in another chat. You didn't lose
the back. they didn't fix it. Just a a a
thing I I I learned is that you can just
copy the entire set of instructions,
paste it in another chat, and it
sometimes work with a few tweaks.
Uh and yeah, that's like the most
important uh thing I learned. Um and and
also take um into consideration that
some programs don't need the full chain.
You can just report the data inflation.
But I I would say it is important to
show you can leak sensitive data and not
and not just
regular data. Uh,
and basically another thing I I will say
is Marttown is just the beginning.
Yes. Agreed, man. Agreed. All right,
great tips. Let's cut it there. Leave
that for the listeners to go. Thanks for
coming on the podcast, man. I appreciate
it.
Yeah, thank you.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.